Rebecca Gerhard

3455 Riverside Dr. Anderson, CA 96007

T: 530-215-6947

E: rebeccalynngerhard@gmail.com



Summary

Teaching students with special needs has been an incredible opportunity. During my career in the field, I have enjoyed the experience of working with each and every one of my students. I am comfortable working with any level of special needs and have experience in both mild/moderate and moderate/severe classrooms. During my time at Anderson Middle School I have executed excellent classroom management techniques, provided detailed and leveled instruction, established personal relationships with students and parents, fostered commitment towards high expectations, and maintained all legally required documents and IEP regulations. Special Education is incredibly important to me and I absolutely commit myself to providing the best opportunities and education to all my students.

Experience

Education Specialist, Anderson Middle School

Anderson, CA — 2011-Current

Delivered instruction in a wide range of academic subjects, life skills, and other areas of need, maintained and developed IEPs, managed paraprofessional staff, and provided special education services for Special Day Class students.

Accomplishments

- Pro-Act certified Trainer with SCOE
- CA clear credential in both mild/mod and mod/severe
- IEP knowledge and expertise
- High rate of successful CAPA test scores
- Experience in mild/moderate and moderate/severe SDC class
- 6th grade Girl's Basketball Coach (3 years)
- BTSA mentor and University Supervisor for fellow teachers

Previous Work Experience:

- SDC Teacher Great Partnership: Summer of 2014
- Transcripts Specialist Humboldt State: 2006-2010
- Yosemite View Restaurant, Evergreen Lodge, New Fountain Apartments (management), Barnes & Noble (cafe manager) 2002-2006

Education

Humboldt State University

BA and Ed. Specialist Credentials mild/mod and mod/severe — 2006-2010

Frostburg State University and Saint Vincent College 1999-2001